<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Mohsen Biglari</title>
    <link>http://mbt925.github.io/projects/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Mohsen Biglari</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 03 Jan 2022 15:22:45 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://mbt925.github.io/projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>BazarKhodro</title>
      <link>http://mbt925.github.io/projects/bazarkhodro/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jan 2022 15:22:45 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mbt925.github.io/projects/bazarkhodro/</guid>
      <description>Using BazarKhodro, one can sell a used car, or buy one. Searching is possible using multiple filters and orderings, together with marking and adding notes to certion results. Users can be notificed based on different triggers, e.g., availability of a certain make and model, or a certain price threshold for a specific car.
🔗 Google Play
 Screenshots </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chartex</title>
      <link>http://mbt925.github.io/projects/chartex/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jan 2022 13:38:37 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mbt925.github.io/projects/chartex/</guid>
      <description>Chartex started with just domestic flights, then extended with international flights, domestic and international hotels, trains, buses and travel insurances. It has both Android and iOS apps which are identical in terms of features. Chartex was a B2B service. So we had to prepare the apps for different businesses with different themes and requirements. We made necessary ad-hoc tools to make this process as automatic as possible. Starting from customizing the required sections (flight, hotel, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wear Persian Calendar</title>
      <link>http://mbt925.github.io/projects/wear_persian_calendar/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jan 2022 12:05:58 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mbt925.github.io/projects/wear_persian_calendar/</guid>
      <description>Wear Persian Calendar includes a Persian calendar app, two Complications, and a Tile for Wear OS devices. Users will have an up-to-date persian calendar including holidays and events. The current date is observable via different complications or tiles.
🔗 Google Play
 Privacy Policy Wear Persian Calendar app doesn&amp;rsquo;t collect any user data. All data are hosted locally on the device.
 Screenshots </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Baby Nurse | مادریار</title>
      <link>http://mbt925.github.io/projects/babynurse/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 20:38:18 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mbt925.github.io/projects/babynurse/</guid>
      <description>First Persian baby care app for Iranian mothers. This app measures baby&amp;rsquo;s weight, height, and every other required measurement. It also records diaper changes, breastfeedings, sleep, medications, vaccinations, diaries, bottle feedings, foods, baths, doctor visitations, activities, and teeth details. A busy mother won&amp;rsquo;t forget anything about her child because everything will be reminded to her, e.g., today is the vaccination day, or now is the time for a diaper change.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
